akispetretzikis.com 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy

AKIS PETRETZIKIS LTD is the manager of the website akispetretzikis.com.

This privacy policy explains what kind of information we may gather when you visit our website or when what kind of information we may gather when you use our services. It is multilayered so you can easily find the reason for which we process your personal data and how they are used. Thus, we encourage you to carefully read this Privacy Policy and select the option “I agree” if you agree with the terms of this document.

  1. **Processing** **Manager** **–** ** _[Contact Details](https://akispetretzikis.com/el/contacts)_**
  2. **Where do we store the information you have provided**
  3. **Who** **has** **access** **to** **your** **data**
  4. **What** **information** **is** **collected**

**A. Browsing the Website**

**B. Creating an Account on the Website**

**C. Information you share when you comment on our recipes**

**D. Recipe book**

**E. Participation in seminars**

**F. Participation in contests**

**G. Subscription to our e-newsletter**

**H. Data Processing for advertisement purposes**

**I. Social Media**

**G. Links to other websites**

**J. Push notifications**

**K. Contacting us – Customer service**

**L. Applying for a job**

**5.  Your rights**

**6\. When will we respond to requests concerning personal data?**

**7\. To whom can you appeal?**

**8\. How will you remain updated about changes in the Privacy Policy**

**1.** **Processing** **Manager** **–** **Contact** **Details**

The company “AKIS PETRETZIKIS LTD” GEMI (General Commercial Registry) 128447403000, based in Agia Paraskevi of Attica, 2 Tassopoulou street, and 16 Elvetias street, legally represented, is responsible for processing personal data collected by you.

For general information, you can contact us on info@akispetretzikis.com, or call us on 2169001112, or send a mail to the address above. You can also contact us via _[ Facebook messenger](https://www.facebook.com/akispetretzikisofficialpage/)_.

**2\. Where do we store the information you have provided?**

The information we collect is stored within the European Economic Area.

**3\. Who has access to your data?**

Only the people responsible for each department of the company (department heads) have access to your personal data. Your personal data will be used exclusively for the purposes stated each time and the information will not be disclosed or sold to third parties for other, irrelevant, purposes.

We work with third companies for some processes and transmit some of your personal data to them or they have access to your data through our website. This is only so that we can provide services. You can find who has access to your data below.

**4.** **Information** **we** **collect**

Our company learns about you either via our website or via the various activities we organize. It is very important to use to know your interests and worries because it allows us to improve and offer better services to you.

There are various ways through which you can share your data with us:

In most cases, you provide your personal data directly through the various forms you send or we receive (mainly via our website).

For example:

By subscribing to our website

  * When you contact us
  * When you participate in contests

In other cases, we collect the information (for example when we use cookies to make browsing on the website easier and understand how you use the website).

You can find the cases that involve processing your personal data, their purpose and description listed below.

Remember, it is your responsibility to ensure that the data you provide is true and accurate. Users will be responsible for the inaccuracy of such data as well as for any damages that might be caused. Our company reserves the right to cease all relations with a user for the aforementioned reasons.

**Α.** **Browsing** **the** **Website**

When browsing the website, the following information is sent by your browser to our website without any action on your part (passively):

  * Your device’s IP address that made the URL request on our website.
  * Date and time of access.
  * Name and URL of the file requested.
  * The referrer-URL.
  * The browser you use, the operating system of the computer with internet access as well as the access provider.
  * The geolocation of your browser, operating system or other settings of your terminal, if you have agreed to it.

All of the data listed above are temporarily stored in a log file.

**Purpose and Lawful Basis for Processing**

The purpose of everything listed above is to guarantee a proper connection establishment and an easy browsing of the website and the safety and stability of the system.

The lawful basis for processing if Article 6 par.1 section F pf GDPR, which allows us to process data when it is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests.

**For how long is the information stored?**

Data are stored temporarily for the duration of the session and then they are automatically deleted. When you stop using our website, geolocational information is deleted.

**Who has access  to your data?**

\- We work with the company E-Productions – Evthimios Kokkinopoulos that **manages** our website. Guest user cookies are automatically deleted when the browser is closed.

For more information, you can visit the website of eproductions _[here](https://eproductions.gr/)_.

\- We work with the company “RELEVANCE ONLINE MARKETING CONSULTING BOUTIQUE O.E. under the distinctive title RELEVANCE OE for the creation and management of Google Analytics and Google AdWords and to generally provide consulting services of Internet advertisement https://relevance.gr/

**Β** **. Creating an account on our website**

**Purpose and lawful basis for processing**

The purpose for collecting your personal data is to provide personalized services and manage your account.

The lawful basis for processing is your compliance based on Article 1 par. 1 section A of GDPR

**Information** **we** **need**

To subscribe to our website, should you wish to, you can provide us with contact information, your name, and surname.

Browsing our website your IP address and the last time you logged in are automatically sent to us.

We will also process the following cookie data:

Browsing history in our website

**Why we need the information?**

We need the aforementioned information to offer easier access to our website.

If you wish you can receive newsletters. We will suggest new recipes to you and you can receive announcements regarding contests. For more information, you can visit the section of this document concerning the **e-newsletter here**.

**For how long is the information stored?**

We store your data for as long as you use your account or up to five years. At that time, we will ask for your consent again. You have the right, at any given time, to delete your account. If you do so, your data will be deleted, unless there is another reason mandating that they are kept.

**Who** **  has access to ** **your** **data?**

\- We work with the company E-Productions – Evthimios Kokkinopoulos that manages our website. E-productions collects user log in data which are stored in the company’s servers in Germany. Data collected by E-productions are stored for up to a year.

For more information, you can visit the website of eproductions _[here](https://eproductions.gr/)_.

\- We work with the company “RELEVANCE ONLINE MARKETING CONSULTING BOUTIQUE O.E. under the distinctive title RELEVANCE OE for the creation and management of Google Analytics and Google AdWords and to generally provide consulting services of Internet advertisement.

**C. INFORMATION YOU SHARE WHEN YOU COMMENT ON RECIPES**

**Purpose** **and** **lawful** **basis for processing**

You can comment under recipes posted on our website or make questions about them.

You can comment as long as you are logged in as a user on our website, or through social media, or through the Disqus platform.

Lawful basis for processing is your compliance based on Article 1 par. 1 section A of GDPR, that is the legitimate interest of our company, in that way we respond to the users of our website and improve our services.

**Information** **we** **need**

When you comment using your social media account, we don’t store any personal information, apart from what is publicly available in the comment through the Disqus platform (for example the name of the account, profile photo or photos you share in the comments) or if you yourselves upload more data, like for example, photos.

When you comment using your website account, we process the data you have already provided to open your account.

**Why is the information needed?**

Your comments or questions along with any other data you might choose to share with us (like the name and the profile photo in social media) are stored in the website to help the rest of the users – visitors when making the suggested recipes.

**For how long is the information stored?**

You can delete your comments at your own discretion or ask us to do it for you.

**Who**   **has access to your  ** **data?**

You can also comment on our website through **Disqus Inc** , which is based in the United States of America. Disqus Inc is a company certified with the EU – US Privacy Shield. You can see the policy _[here](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy)_.

We work with the company E-Productions – Evthimios Kokkinopoulos that **manages** our website. E-productions collects user log in data which are stored in the company’s servers in Germany. Data collected by E-productions are stored for up to a year.

For more information, you can visit the website of eproductions _[ here](https://eproductions.gr/)_.

**D. Recipe Book**

You can save your favorite recipes in our Recipe Book.

Lawful basis for processing is Article 6 par. 1 section A of GDCR

**Information** **we** **need**

When creating the Recipe Book using your social media account, we store no personal information.

When creating the Recipe Book through your website account, we process data you have already provided when you opened your account (name and surname) and your email.  

**Why is the information needed?**

We need the aforementioned information to offer you the service of the Recipe Book.

**For how long is the information stored?**

We use your personal data for as long as you have your account or for up to five years. At that time, we will ask for your consent again. You have the right, at any given time, to delete your account. When you do so, your data will be deleted, unless there is another reason mandating that they are kept.

**Who has access to your data?**

We work with the company E-Productions – Evthimios Kokkinopoulos that **manages** our website. E-productions collects user log in data which are stored in the company’s servers in Germany. Data collected by E-productions are stored for up to a year.

For more information, you can visit the website of eproductions _[ here](http://https/eproductions.gr/)_.

**Ε** **. Participation in Seminars**

Our company acts as the processor of all data provided to it by AKIS PETRETZIKIS ESHOP EE concerning seminars.

Personal data we process for the seminars’ contract are the following:

  * Name and surname
  * Contact phone

We need the aforementioned information to make easier your presence in the seminar and to contact you regarding the seminar.

We keep the aforementioned information only for the seminars and delete them when they are over.

**F** **.** **Participation** **in** **Contests**

**Purpose** **and** **Lawful** **Basis for Processing**

Through our website, newsletter or social media, you can participate in contests we organize from time to time.

The lawful basis for processing is your compliance based on article 1 par. 1 section A of GDPR.

**Why we need the information?**

For your participation, we need only your name and email and in some cases your phone in order to contact you.

If you participate in a contest via your account or social media, we process the account’s data that are public.

**How long are the information stored?**

Your personal information is deleted one month after the contest’s end and the winners are announced, or if you have chosen to subscribe in one of our other services (for example, newsletter).

In the case of a material prize, the winner’s information is stored for two years, which is also the length of the guarantee so you can replace or repair your prize if there is some defect.

**Who has access to your data?**

The data is transmitted only if it is necessary to complete the contest (for example if the contest is made on behalf of a company offering the prize, or if a shipping company is contracted for the shipping of the prize). The relevant information will be written each time in the terms of the contest.

**G. Subscription to our e-newsletter**

**Purpose** **and** **lawful basis for processing**

We collect data to provide this service in order to keep you updated about new recipes, contests and with news of our company. With the data we collect, we create a profile in which the physical address and/or email address are filed in order to better adjust the newsletter and advertisements to your interests.

The lawful basis for processing is your consent based on Article 6, par.1, section A of GDPR.

**What information do we need?**

Your name and email address.

**Who has access to your data?**

We work with Grammedia LTD to send emails. Grammedia provides us with the Contact Pigeon service.

With your consent concerning the receipt of an electronic bulletin, your data are sent to Grammedia LTD which offers us the Contact Pigeon platform. Through this platform, we analyze your behavior on our website and our newsletters. This means that we collect data and receive updates regarding the receipt of our newsletters, if you have opened them and data regarding your browsing, like geographical location, IP address, device which you used during your visit, browser. In addition, we might collect information linked to third parties, like demographical information or browsing data.

To ensure that no error was made during entering your email address, we have a double-opt-in process established: When you enter your email address in the predefined field, we will send you a confirmation email. Only if you select the confirmation link your email address will be sent to Grammedia LTD to receive e-newsletters.

**For how long are the information you provided kept?**

Your data for the newsletter as well as data collected from emails and statistical data will be kept for as long as we have your permission to send you newsletters. If you are not opening the newsletters for the period of a full year, we will consider your account to be inactive and will notify you for the deletion of your account from the receivers’ lists.

**You can revoke your permission for the newsletter at any time if you unsubscribe via our website. You can find the link in the end of each newsletter.**

In addition, in case you wish to do so, you can at any time unsubscribe from the updates list by sending an email to _[privacy@contactpigeon.com](mailto:privacy@contactpigeon.com)_. You can also remove all data that might have been collected during your browsing. ContactPigeon will process and carry out your request within a reasonable period of time from the notification date.

For more information you can read the privacy policy _[here](http://http/pages.contactpigeon.com/privacy-policy)_.

**H** **.** **Processing** **Data** **for** **Advertisement** **Purposes**

**Google** **Analytics**

When you visit akispetretzikis.com, we use Google Analytics to collect log files and details concerning your browsing on our website.

Data collected include:

  * IP address of the device that has access to the Internet and made the URL request.
  * Date and time of access.
  * Name and URL of the file requested.
  * The referrer-URL.
  * Browser you use, operating system of your computer with Internet access, as well as the access provider are all stored in a log file.
  * The operating system of your portable device, if you are visiting the website through a portable device.
  * The type of the portable device and its settings.
  * Serial number of the portable device.
  * The redirecting website (the website that directed you to hours).
  * Action regarding the way you are using our website, like the sections you visit.

The website might collect information about the exact location of the device using geographical location and technologies like GPS, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth or Cell tower proximity. The majority of portable devices and browsers give you the ability to revoke the consent you gave us for the collection of the aforementioned data, using your device settings or browser settings. If you have questions regarding how you can block information about your geographical location, contact your provider or the manufacturer of the device or your software or browser provider. All of the aforementioned information is processed **anonymously**.

Data are stored for 50 months for marketing and statistical purposes and then are automatically deleted. When you stop using our website, your geolocational data are deleted.

**Cookies**

You can read more about cookies we use **here**

You can stop the installation of cookies recording all of the aforementioned information regarding browsing in our website through your browser settings. However, if you do so, you might not be able to use the full range of services of our website.

You can also block the analysis of data created by the website’s cookies and regard its usage (including the IP address) as well as processing these data by Google if you load and install the relevant browser app. Instead of the browser app, you can block analysis by Google Analytics by clicking this _[link](http://chrome/settings/clearBrowserData)_.

An opt-out cookie which blocks future analysis of your data when visiting this website is thus created. The opt-out cookie concerns only this browser and only our website and is stored only in your device. If you delete cookies from this browser you must save the opt-out cookie again. For more information regarding personal data protection with regards to Google Analytics visit Google’s page _[here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=el)_.

**Purpose** **and**   **lawful basis for processing**

The purpose of collecting your personal data is to analyze your online behavior with regards to our online presence as well as the updates we send you. We analyze the sections of the website you visit and which links you click while there.

The lawful basis for processing is the legitimate interest of the company based on Article 6 par.1 section F of GDPR. If you have given your consent (for example for the receipt of e-newsletters), lawful basis for processing your consent based on Article 6 par.1 section A of GDPR. Data processing of clients for marketing purposes is considered as a legitimate interest of our company.

**What information do we collect?**

Each time you visit our website, your web address and last time you logged in are sent to us.

**Why do we need the information?**

We collect data to provide this service in order to keep you updated about new recipes, contests and with news of our company. With the data we collect, we create a profile in which the physical address and/or email address are listed in order to better adjust the newsletter and advertisements to your interests.

**Right of Objection**

You can file an objection against processing your data for the aforementioned purposes at any time and with no cost by contacting us  _[here](https://akispetretzikis.com/el/contacts)_

**For how long is the information kept?**

The data are deleted if you revoke your permission from the email distributors or if you revoke your consent to individual advertising media or object to certain advertising mediums. In addition, if you exercise the right of objection, your electronic contact address will be excluded from any advertisement data processing, within a reasonable time period.

**Who has access to your data?**

We work with the company E-Productions – Evthimios Kokkinopoulos that **manages** our website. Guest user cookies are automatically deleted when the browser is closed. Guest user cookies are deleted with the termination of the session.

For more information, you can visit the website of eproductions _[here.](https://eproductions.gr/)_

We work with the company “RELEVANCE ONLINE MARKETING CONSULTING BOUTIQUE O.E. under the distinctive title RELEVANCE OE for the **creation and management of Google Analytics and Google AdWords and to generally provide consulting services of Internet advertisement**.

We work with Grammedia LTD to send mails. Grammedia offers us the services of the Contact Pigeon platform.

We will keep the information you have provided to send you newsletters for as long as we have your permission.

You can revoke your permission to receive newsletters at any time if you unsubscribe via the website. You can find the link to unsubscribe at the end of each newsletter.

In addition, should you wish to, you can at any given time unsubscribe from the updates list by sending an email to _[privacy@contactpigeon.com](mailto:privacy@contactpigeon.com)_ but to also remove all data that are possibly collected during your browsing history. ContactPigeon will process your request within a reasonable time period from the date it was made.

For more information, click _[here](http://pages.contactpigeon.com/privacy-policy)_.

**I** **.** **Social** **Media**

We use social media plugins to personalize our website. You can also log in our website through your Facebook account.

In every page, we have a plugin and your browser will link to Facebook and will load content from these web pages. Your browsing to our website might be monitored by the aforementioned social media, even if you are not active on them. When you access our website via social media, the website automatically stores your email address (as it is on Facebook). You can then browse in the same manner as the users of the website.

The company also maintains its own pages on social media (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram).

Any content sent to our website via social media or social media pages of the company might be public. For that reason, be careful when you provide personal information.

Social media provide detailed information about the application field, nature, and purpose of your data processing on their web pages.

**J** **.** **Links** **to** **other** **websites**

You can find links to partner websites, advertisement and other third parties that are not covered in this document on our website.  We encourage you to read first the privacy policy of the websites you visit, before disclosing any personal information on them.

**K. Push Notifications**

You can receive notifications about our special offers and our news depending on the device with which you browse on our website.

To turn off notifications, follow the instructions below:

−  Desktop: Right click on the notification > Turn off notifications by akiseshop.com  
−  Mobile: Go to Notifications center > Website settings > Notifications > Turn off notifications by akiseshop.com  
−  Browsers:

• Google Chrome: Settings > Show advanced settings – Content settings > Enter akiseshop.com and select “Block”.  
• Mozilla Firefox: Setting > Content > Notifications – Select > akiseshop.com – “Remove website”  
• Safari: Preferences > Notifications > Select “Block”

**L** **.** **Contact** **us**

**Purpose** **and** **lawful** **basis for processing**

Each time you reach out to us with general questions regarding the company or our products – services, we keep the information you provide in order to answer.

The lawful basis for processing is Article 6 par.1 section F of GDPR, that is the legitimate interest of our company.

**What information** do we need **?**

We need information regarding you so that we can contact you. More specifically, we need your name, phone number and email address as well as the content of letters or emails you have sent us.

**Why is the information needed?**

We use this information to answer and process your requests and maintain a file with our communication.

**For how long is the information stored?**

The information is deleted six months after our last contact with you.

**M** **.** **Applying** **for** **a** **job**

**Purpose** **and** **lawful basis for processing**

We collect information to evaluate whether you are suited for the job opening.

The lawful basis for processing is Article 6, par.1 section B of GDPR concerning the necessary processing to draft a contract or to take action at your request before concluding a contract.

**Why is the information needed?**

We will use the information provided by you to evaluate your job application. We will not give the information to third parties for commercial purposes.

We will use the information to contact you. We will use the rest of the information to evaluate whether you are suited for the job opening.

We request no additional information from what we need and do not keep them for more than is necessary.

The information requested is relevant to the specific job opening.

  * Application process

During this process, we need personal information like your name and contact information. In addition, we need prior experience and studies.

  * Selection process

Our human resources personnel will evaluate your application and call you to schedule an interview so they will select the right person for the job. At no point in the selection process will the candidates be evaluated based on a public social media profile.

  * Job offer – job acceptance

Should you accept the job offer, we will request additional information in order to proceed with the hiring process.

The information will be what is required to register you in the ERGANI system of the Ministry of Labor, Social Insurance, and Social Solidarity. Meaning, your name, surname, parents’ names, date of birth, ID number, VAT number, Tax Office, Social Security Number, home address, email address, marital status, bank account number, amount of pay. In addition, depending on the job responsibilities, we might request a copy of your ID or passport, and certifications of studies and foreign languages.

**For how long is the information stored?**

Applications, resumes, and information which are sent and immediately rejected will be deleted – destroyed within a month after the position is filled.

Applications, resumes, and information which are sent and evaluated will be deleted – destroyed within six months after the position is filled.

If the worker is hired, all the data concerning him/her, including remunerations and reasons for terminating the contract will be deleted twenty (20) years after the termination of the contract.

Supporting documents regarding maternity leaves and sick leaves will be deleted five (5) years after the time they were received.

**Who**   **has access to your  data?**

Your information, which is necessary for the submission of tax and insurance data, as well as payments, are sent to the Unitax accounting office and possibly to our legal department.

In addition, we work with EFG Eurobank Ergasias and Piraeus Bank to pay salaries.

**5\. Your rights**

We will keep the confidentiality of your personal data and ensure that you can exercise your rights. You can exercise your rights without any cost, sending us an email to the address (hr@akispetretzikis.com) simply stating the reason for your request and the right you wish to exercise or by applying _[here](https://akispetretzikis.com/el/contacts)_.

If we think it is necessary to confirm your ID, we might request a copy that proves your identity.

Regardless of the purpose or lawful basis for processing basis according to which we process your data, you have the following rights:

  * **Right of information** : You have the right to be informed about the way we use your personal data and about your rights.
  * **Right of access** to your personal data. You have the right to remain updated about whether we process your data. If we do, you have the right to remained updated on the purpose of the processing, the kind of data we keep about you, to whom we give data to, for how long they are stored, if there is automated decision making and for the rest of your rights, like right to correct, delete or limit processing and to file complaint to the Data Protection Authority.
  * **Right to correct** incorrect personal data. If you find an error in your data, you can file a report for us to correct it (for example: correct the name or change your address). If you are a registered user of our website, you can also gain access to the section with your personal data and modify or update the information regarding you. However, actively providing personal data to us for any reason, you guarantee that these data are true and accurate and agree to notify us of any change or update. You have the sole responsibility for any loss or damages caused on the website or the person responsible for the website or any third party due to inaccurate or false information in the registration documents. Please keep in mind that you must provide only your personal data and not data of third parties, except in cases allowed by this Privacy Policy.
  * **Right to delete**. You can request us to delete your data if they are no longer required for the aforementioned process purposes.

However, this right might not be fulfilled if:

  * There is an ongoing legal dispute with our company.
  * The purchase you made has not yet been sent.
  * You have debts to our company.
  * If you have abused our services (for example repeatedly canceling orders) within the last two years.
  * If you have made a purchase by us, we are required to store your tax information for twelve (12) years.
  * You have the **right of transfer** of your data. You can request to receive in written form the data you have provided or request us to relay them to another person responsible for processing.
  * **Right** **to** **limit** **processing**. You can request us to limit the processing of your data for any amount of time the review of your objection is pending.
  * **Right of objection** to the processing of your personal data. You can object to processing your personal data or revoke your compliance and we will stop processing your data if there are no compelling and legitimate reasons to continue.
  * In addition, you have the right to object to the processing of your data for advertising purposes. You can withdraw your consent at any given time:
  * By unsubscribing in the emails.
  * Deactivating **cookies** by changing the settings of your browser. For more information, visit our cookie policy **here**.

Or contact us directly _[here ](https://akispetretzikis.com/el/contacts)_

**6\. When do we respond to requests concerning personal data?**

We respond free of charge, without any delay and within one (1) month upon receiving your request. If, however, your request if complicated or there is a large number of requests, then we will notify you within the month if we need an extension of another two (2) months to answer.

If your requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive due to their repeating nature, the company can charge a reasonable fee, taking under consideration the administrative costs to keep you updated or process your request or disincline to continue processing your request.

**7\. Right to complain to the Supervisory Authority**

You have the right to complain to the supervisory Data Protection Authority, if you think that processing your personal data is violating the current national and regulatory framework law concerning personal data. The competent supervisory authority in Greece is the Data Protection Authority (postal address: 1-3 Kifisias Avenue, Athens /  _[www.dpa.gr](http://www.dpa.gr/)_ , ph. 2106475600).

**8\. How to remain updated for any modifications made to this Privacy Policy.**

We will update this Privacy Policy when necessary. If there are important changes to the Privacy Policy or the way in which we use your personal data, we will publish the changes on our website. We encourage you to periodically read the Privacy Policy so that you know how your data are protected.

If you wish to contact us for any reason regarding the processing of your personal data and exercising your rights, you can call us at 216-9001112 or send an email to [dataprotection@akispetretzikis.com](mailto:dataprotection@akispetretzikis.com)
